DOMINIC LACAILLE

Montreal, Canada

▶ phone +1 (514) 984 0393

in linkedin linkedin.com/in/dominic-lacaille-mtl

summary

Developer with 12 years experience who has designed and developed over 30 web, mobile, and server applications from use cases and functional requirements. His great ease researching and solving complex problems brings a marked advantage in research and development.

work experience

2022–present Senior Front-End Team Lead, Swoo — Brossard

Swoo Agence Numérique

- Leads the Front-End team in numerous web projects
- Implements an agile structure within the company to incite team work and help organize milestones and deadlines
- Trains the team on React, latest accessibility principles, tailwind CSS and best practices
- Develops an maintains a complex Laravel/React website for a foodtech startup
- Maintains and develops new features for WeCook using Laravel/Vue
- Integrates websites in WordPress, including custom themes and plugins

2020–2021 Senior Front-End Dev., Vanilla Forums — Montreal

Vanilla Forums

- Creates an analytics interface in React Typescript with live data
- Develops dynamic customizations to the look and feel of the forum
- Develops a declarative solution for generating complex forms
- Maintains and improves the core of Vanilla Forums and it's plugins in both PHP and React Typescript

2015–2020 Application Software Dev., Voxco — Montreal

Voxco Canada

- Develops an offline survey engine in React
- Develops and designs an offline personal interview application (CAPI) for Android and iOS with over 2,000 monthly active users
- Participates in an Agile team with a fast release cycle
- Develops various APIs to support mobile applications

2012–2015 Full Stack Dev., Appcom — Longueuil

Appcom

- Develops and designs applications for quads, snowmobiles and leisure boats with more than 100,000 downloads on Google Play and Apple App Store, combining cartography technologies and point-of-interest management APIs
- · Develops sales websites for points-of-interest
- DevelopsWordPress websites, plugins and themes in PHP
- Maintains ArcGIS cartography servers and creates tools to manipulate geographical data and generate tiled maps

education

2010–2013 Édouard-Montpetit College — Longueuil

College Diploma Computer Science · Specialization: Business Computing

2013 Java Dev. Intern, McKesson — Montreal

McKesson Canada

Maintains and develops Java web applications for Liferay and PostgreSQL used daily by pharmacists and doctors

personal projects

2019 Findjoo Mobile for Android/iOS

Findjoo Mobile

Cross-platform React Native application. Provides members and event organizers with an easy to use interface to manage their calendar, scan tickets and receive important notifications.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.findjoomobile

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/findjoo

skills

Programming Javascript, TypeScript, Java, Python, C#, PHP 8.1, Objective-C, C++, LATEX, Kotlin, Swift,

Languages EBNF, Regex, SQL

Development NeoVim, VS Code, Visual Studio, Android Studio, Xcode, Sublime Text, Eclipse, Intel-

Environments liJ, Atom

Mobile React Native, iOS, Android

Web React, Redux, Laravel, Tailwind CSS, REST, Apollo GraphQL, .NET Core, Node.js, Vite

Testing Mocha, Jest, Storybook, JUnit, TDD

Project Jira, ZenHub

Management

Databases Realm, SQL Server, Entity Framework, MySQL, PostgreSQL

other information

Languages Français · Langue maternelle

English · Bilingual

Interests Programming · Photography · Music

References upon request

November 30, 2022